Khayyam Jones

(801) 787-7797 khayyam.Jones@gmail.com 105 N 900 E, Provo UT 84606 https://linked.com/in/khayyamjones https://github.com/khayyamj http://khayyam.ga

PROFILE

I am a front end web developer from the Provo, Utah area. My professional experience includes programming in React, Angular, Javascript and Node as well as many other front-end technologies, compilers, and testing frameworks. I love the opportunity to channel large amounts of date into an elegant web solution that creates an amazing user experience. I believe that programming with these object oriented frameworks leads to better code that is more maintainable and scaleable leading reduce spending and saving time.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Languages: React, Angular, Javascript, JSX, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3,

SQL, OOP

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Angular 1.x, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js,

Passport.js, Mocha, Chai, Typescript, Bootstrap

Other Proficiencies: SQL, Postgress, MongoDB, GIT, NPM, GULP, Webpack,

JSON, Yarn, Databases, Atom, Bash, CDN, VIM, AJAX, Axios, Fetch, REST, RESTful API, MVC, Mac OS X, SASS, SCSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Young Living 2015 - 2017 Team Lead

- Helped with testing and development of new chat / email platform; tested basic functionality, load testing, level 1 security, and basic database integrity; contributed to client side and company side UI design.
- Developed new agent reporting program which was used to show agent performance over time (daily, weekly, monthly and quarterly) over the key 5 performance areas.
- Developers new team tracking program for supervising managers to show their team trends, identify key areas of performance and allow tracking of program implementations as well as incentive distribution.
- Data audits; wrote program that imported CSV files, performed basic data audits and reported anomalies that alerted supervisors of problems that needed to be investigated further for corrective action.
- Finding and reporting bugs including all relevant information for duplicating situation and follow-up to ensure bugs had been resolved.

Boy Scouts 2017 - Present Webmaster

- Lone web developer for a local community Boy Scout troop. I was in charge of redesigning and maintaining the troop website using React with Redux, Javascript, Node, and MySQL.
- Utilized end point testing with Mocha and Chai to verify correct data was being returned by the database.

UVRMC 2012 - 2014

Patient Care Technician

Detailed data entry of all patient care including all vital statistics, patient activity, doctor and nurse interactions, and more.

- Analyzing data for use in patient care and in report to Doctors, Nurses and other technicians regarding patient's continuing care.
- Occasional use of high tech equipment for patient resuscitation

OTHER WORK

Strongbrook Consulting Campaign Manager

2013 - 2017

- Built and maintained a Wordpress website for personal consulting business. Responsible for UI design, created content, maintained blog and video posts, and maintaining and updating HTML, CSS and Javascript plugins.
- Campaign manager, utilizing Facebook advertising, web pixel implementation, audience targeting and website SEO optimization.

KSRS Properties 2008 - 2015 Webmaster

- Built and maintained a Wordpress website for small real estate investing company. Responsible for updating front page and blog content, monitoring comments, updating themes; used HTML and CSS for minor site modifications.
- Linked website for social media including direct links, automatic posting, advertising referrals.
- Monitored and optimized website for SEO including keyword searches, content optimization, and video optimization.
- Directed advertising campaigns and campaign management including pay per click, per pay view, ad pixels, and ad targeting on Facebook and Google.

KhayyamJones.com Personal Website

2002 - Present

- Built a personal website using HTML and CSS and Javascript plugins.
- Refactored website utilizing Wordpress and customizable themes.
- Utilized various online technologies designed for lead generation and website analytics

EDUCATION

Brigham Young University -

2002

MA in Dance Pedagogy

Brigham Young University -

1998

BS in Mathematics

Certifications:

DevMountain

2017

Javascript Web Development